# ALEXSANDRIA RYAN

(she / her) ENG / FR

**902 476 8867** 

Halifax, NS

github.com/AlexsandriaRyan

alexsandria.netlify.app

alinkedin.com/in/alexsandriaryan

### **SKILLS**

♦ C / C++ / C#

. .

♦ Java

→ JavaScript→ HTML / CSS /

SCSS

♦ Android Development ♦ PHP

♦ SQL

♦ Git♦ Adobe XD

→ Google Suite

→ Google Suit→ WordPress

♦ Jira

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Codecademy**: Learn JavaScript *September 2022* 

September 2022

DELF (Diplôme d'Études en Langue

Française): Level B2

April 2014

### VOLUNTEERING

### **FRAG for Cancer**

Cosplay Competition Judge
November 2018 Halifax, NS

Worked with a team of cosplay judges to inspect costumes worn and presented by local costumers. Awarded prizes based on competition level and workmanship in sewing, foamsmithing, and crafting.

### **Nova Scotia Kiwanis Music Festival**

Adjudicator's Assistant / Registration April 2013 – May 2018 Halifax, NS

Aided adjudicator with time management, handling and writing official documents, and reviewing performances. Greeted guests and competitors for each event.

### **ABOUT ALEX**

Recent and accomplished graduate from Nova Scotia Community College with a diploma in IT Programming. With 10 years of service experience, a Bachelor of Music, and an ever-growing portfolio of IT projects, I strive to combine my passions for creativity, language, and problem-solving as a developer.

### **EDUCATION**

# Diploma in IT Programming

Nova Scotia Community College Halifax, NS January 2022 — December 2023

# Bachelor of Music in Composition

Dalhousie University Halifax, NS September 2014 — December 2018

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Nova Scotia Community College: Student

January 2022 – December 2023 Halifax, NS

- ❖ Programming: learned and applied object-oriented programming principles; built several programs to meet specific requirements; consistently practiced organized, clean code. Currently enrolled in courses for C#, C++, and Android development.
- ♦ Web Design: learned about design principles and processes and applied knowledge to create an e-Portfolio website, including mocks.
- Databases: learned and applied advanced SQL concepts such as DDL, DML, Stored Procedures, and Triggers. Applied knowledge to projects in C# and PHP
- Various courses: excelled in various courses related to operating systems, quality testing, systems analysis, networking, and professional development.

### **VERB Interactive: Junior WordPress Developer**

April 2023 – Present Halifax, NS

- ♦ Manage tickets via JIRA system to handle various tasks, including new website builds, bugs, maintenance, and updates.
- ♦ Collaborate with a variety of teams, including creative, accounts, quality assurance, management, and other developers.
- Work for and with high-profile clients while producing work that meets high expectations and meeting deliverables in a timely, orderly, and efficient manner.
- Create documents to support quality assurance testing on new builds, including screenshots, locations, fixes, suggestions, and other important information. Shared documents with team to tackle updates before launching builds.

### Joanne Pullin Limited: Web Developer

May 2021 – Present Halifax, NS

- Re-designed and built two websites for Joanne's businesses in real estate and dog breeding (joannepullinrealtor.ca and roamingrovers.ca).
- ♦ Periodically maintain website as needed.

# ALEXSANDRIA RYAN

(she / her)

#### 

902 476 8867

Halifax, NS

github.com/AlexsandriaRyan

alexsandria.netlify.app

alinkedin.com/in/alexsandriaryan

### **AWARDS**

### **NSCC Student Interview Competition**

2<sup>nd</sup> Place April 2023

## The Women Innovating in Nova Scotia (WINS) Bursary

September 2022

### Your Goals, Your Future! Award

September 2022

### The Union of National Defence Employees Memorial Scholarship

December 2018

## Fountain School of Performing Arts Undergraduate Scholarship

November 2018 and November 2017

### Ian Perry-Berger Memorial Music Bursary

March 2018 and March 2017

### F. Hume Wells Scholarship

November 2014

### J&A Campbell Memorial Scholarship

November 2014

### **Evanov Radio Group Scholarship**

September 2014

#### **Helena Evans Memorial Scholarship**

June 2014

#### **Seamus Flynn Award**

June 2014

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONT.

### Joanne Pullin Limited: Administrative Assistant

May 2021 – April 2023 Halifax, NS

- ♦ Designed and maintained intricate Google Sheets for the purpose of client management and paycheque / commission calculations.
- ♦ Assisted in everyday tasks and support, including the managing, filing, and optimization of physical and electronic documents.
- ♦ Designed and ordered marketing materials, including mail flyers, business cards and social media posts.
- Created How-To documentation and videos to help onboard new staff and Joanne in daily tasks.

# Manulife Bank: Bilingual Customer Service Professional (ENG/FR)

July 2019 – May 2021 Halifax, NS

- ♦ Promoted to offline team after 6 months; responsible for managing several client and advisor email inboxes and callback requests.
- Maintained digital databases with sensitive client and company information, updating them as required.
- Assisted with company-wide software shift by proposing and spearheading feedback collection, documenting errors, and meeting regularly with our Salesforce team to present reports.
- ♦ Created and maintained a document of over 150+ pages filled with email templates in both English and French to increase productivity.

### O2 Wellness: Receptionist | Front Desk Team Lead

August 2018 – July 2019 Bedford, NS

- ♦ Promoted from Receptionist to Team Lead after 4 months.
- ♦ Established new processes and documents to enhance communication, workplace productivity, and consistency.
- ♦ Managed overdue account collections by emailing and/or calling clients.
- ♦ Worked alone and unsupervised while exercising exceptional time management during high-demand hours.

### Miscellaneous Service Roles

August 2012 - September 2018 Dartmouth & Halifax, NS

- ♦ Walmart, Petro Canada, Sears, and Koodo Mobile
- ❖ Greeted clients and helped them complete purchases, locate items, troubleshoot issues, and promote sales.
- ♦ Maintained knowledge of Apple and Android operating systems and devices, including updates, device setup, known issues, and device-specific information.